<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An appeal most humble yet most earnestly by the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and our gathering together unto him, even adjuring the consideration of the most contrary minded who love his appearing concerning the Scripture on due compare, speaking expresly, or word for word : of the thousand years state of the saints, the dead raised first, and of the living, the remaining chang'd in it : and of the wicked-dead-raised, the Gog Magog under it / by T.B.</title>
            <author>Beverley, Thomas.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1691</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 59 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 16 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A27581</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B2121</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R31270</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11870659</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11870659</idno>
            <idno type="VID">50119</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A27581)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 50119)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 996:27)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An appeal most humble yet most earnestly by the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, and our gathering together unto him, even adjuring the consideration of the most contrary minded who love his appearing concerning the Scripture on due compare, speaking expresly, or word for word : of the thousand years state of the saints, the dead raised first, and of the living, the remaining chang'd in it : and of the wicked-dead-raised, the Gog Magog under it / by T.B.</title>
                  <author>Beverley, Thomas.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 10, 2, 11-12 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Salusbury ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1691.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint information from NUC pre-1956 imprints.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: t.p. cropped at the bottom.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Resurrection --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Geremy Carnes</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:50119:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>AN Appeal moſt Humble, YET Moſt Earneſtly by the Coming OF OUR Lord Jeſus Chriſt, AND Our Gathering together unto HIM, Even Adjuring the CONSIDERATION OF THE <hi>Moſt Contrary Minded,</hi> Who love HIS Appearing: Concerning the Scripture on due Compare, Speaking Expreſly, or Word for Word.</p>
            <p>Of the Thouſand Years State of the Saints; The Dead Raiſed Firſt, and of The Living, The Remaining Chang'd in it.</p>
            <p>And of the Wicked-Dead-Raiſed, the <hi>Gog Magog</hi> under it.</p>
            <p>By <hi>T. B.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="preface">
            <pb facs="tcp:50119:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>THE ADVERTISEMENT TO THE READER.</head>
            <p>MY firſt Intention was only by way of Propoſal, concerning the Saints in the <hi>1000</hi> Years <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt;</hi> But finding Scripture-Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence Riſing ſo high concerning the <hi>Wicked-Dead,</hi> the <hi>Gog Magog</hi> of the <hi>1000</hi> Years alſo Raiſed, but to a State of <hi>Death,</hi> and ſo call'd ſtill, The <hi>Dead.</hi> It Gave me the Boldneſs to Raiſe my Propoſal to an Appeal; My Aſſurance in Theſe Things is, that the <hi>Spirit</hi> by laying its words in one Scripture, to its words in other Scriptures, ſpeaks <gap reason="foreign">
                  <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
               </gap> Expreſly, or word for word of Theſe Things; ſo that the Ring of Truth concerning the <hi>Reſurrection</hi> Broken between, eſpecially, the Apoſtle <hi>Paul,</hi> and the <hi>Apocalyptic</hi> Apoſtle, by laying Them toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, meets, and <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nites; which is the Greateſt Aſſurance that can be Given; Thus It is concerning the Saints; And thus It is concerning the <hi>Wicked Dead,</hi> the <hi>Gog Magog</hi> Raiſed to Condemnation.</p>
            <p>Whoever would diſprove what I have Aſſerted, I expect, He ſhould not only per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plex what I have ſaid, with Enſnaring Queſtions; For ſo Things moſt clear, moſt certain may be perplex'd, but either lay down by the ſame Scripture Contexture a contrary, or different <hi>Scheme,</hi> or at leaſt ſhew this Inconſiſtent with Scripture, or with it ſelf.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="part">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:50119:3"/>
            <head>A moſt Humble, and (I cannot but hope) A moſt Modeſt Propoſal to the Reverend Paſtors, and to All others that diſſent from, or doubt of the <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> and will give Leave to Scripture-Search, and Conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration concerning it.</head>
            <p>THE Propoſal is this: I will here ſingle out Three Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Taken from Plain, Doctrinal, <hi>Apoſtolical,</hi> and from <hi>Prophetical</hi> Scripture in Compare; and which may ſeem of all other moſt diſputable; and if They can be made Good, They will undeniably prove the <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom:</hi> And if They can be made void; They ſhall ſtand a Witneſs againſt me, that I am not able to make Good the <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> I have ſo earneſtly endeavour'd to Aſſert.</p>
            <p>And that They may be more Clearly, and with All Brevity ſeen in their Force I will offer Them in the moſt Argumentative Order, and Form, I can Conveniently for General underſtanding compoſe Them into.</p>
            <div n="1" type="argument">
               <head>Argument 1.</head>
               <p>If the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>New Earth,</hi> the Scripture ſpeaks of, be prepar'd for the <hi>Thouſand Years Reign of Chriſt,</hi> and of his <hi>Saints,</hi> ſo as to Begin, when that Begins, and to End, when that Ends; Then there muſt be a <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt;</hi> But ſo It will be Found by a Compare of the moſt Litteral Conſequences from <hi>Doctrinal,</hi> and <hi>Prophetical Texts</hi> compar'd: Therefore ſo it muſt be.</p>
               <p>I will here Anticipate one Evaſion; Seeing All <hi>Prophetical</hi> Scriptures of the Old Teſtament, particularly the mention of the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>New Earth, Eſay</hi> 65. 17, and <hi>c.</hi> 66. 22. are ſo poſitive; and that in the New Teſtament, There is mention of the <hi>Regeneration, viz.</hi> of All Things, <hi>Matth.</hi> 19. 28. of <hi>Times of Refreſhing;</hi> or <hi>Reſouling of All Things;</hi> of the <hi>Time of the Reſtitution of All Things</hi> at the <hi>Coming of Chriſt;</hi> For the <hi>Heavens</hi> muſt Receive Him, till then; And that this <hi>Reſtitution</hi> was ſpoken of by the <hi>Mouth of All his Prophets, ſince the World began,</hi> Acts 3. 19, 20, 21. and that the Apoſtle, <hi>Rom.</hi> 8. 19. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> plainly Aſſerts the Reſtoration of the <hi>Creation,</hi> (Tranſlated <hi>Creature</hi>) in which <hi>Heaven,</hi> and <hi>Earth,</hi> muſt needs be; Seeing All this is ſo; No one ſhall Fly off, and ſay; All this is but <hi>Allegory, Metaphor,</hi> and <hi>Figure;</hi> For with ſuch, There can be no Argument on Scripture Text held.</p>
               <div type="section">
                  <head>Having thus premis'd, I carry on the Argument.</head>
                  <p>If the Apoſtle <hi>John</hi> ſaw, together with the <hi>Holy City,</hi> prepared as a <hi>Bride,</hi> a <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>New Earth,</hi> and that the Former <hi>Firſt Heaven,</hi>
                     <pb n="2" facs="tcp:50119:4"/> and the <hi>Firſt Earth,</hi> were paſs'd away; which <hi>City</hi> will preſently Appear to have a <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> Peace, and Glory; Then the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>New Earth</hi> Begin, when the <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> State of the <hi>Holy City</hi> Begins. But ſo He Aſſerts; <hi>I ſaw a New Heaven,</hi> and a <hi>New Earth,</hi> and the <hi>Firſt paſs'd away, Revel.</hi> 21. 1. and then to make it moſt Emphatical, He ſays; <hi>I John ſaw the Holy City, v.</hi> 2. So that it is not to bee ſuppoſed Any One will deny the <hi>Holy City,</hi> and the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and the <hi>New Earth to be Together,</hi> according to the Apoſtle <hi>John,</hi> beſides the Great Concurrences of Reaſon, that ſuch a Glorious State, if Any ſhould have a <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and a <hi>New Earth.</hi> Thus They Began together</p>
                  <p>When any one Compares this with the Apoſtle <hi>Peter</hi>'s Poſitive Aſſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of a <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>Earth, wherein Righteouſneſe ſhall dwell at the Day of Chriſt;</hi> and that a <hi>Day with the Lord</hi> is as a <hi>Thouſand Years;</hi> and ſees here a <hi>City,</hi> (as will be ſeen) of a <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> State of Peace, and, as ſecur'd from <hi>Sathan,</hi> of <hi>Righteouſneſs;</hi> They muſt be very Averſe to Compare of Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, that will not ſuppoſe them to Expound and Illuſtrate one Another, and would Abſolutely diſcourage All Compare of Scripture, which I cannot once ſuppoſe of ſuch Friends of Scripture, as I direct unto.</p>
                  <p>Now that this very <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>New Earth,</hi> and no other <hi>Fly a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way,</hi> after a <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> State of Peace, and <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> Granted to this <hi>Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty,</hi> in a Security from <hi>Sathan,</hi> and ſo end alike; I Go on undeniably to prove.</p>
                  <p>The <hi>Flying away</hi> of whatever <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth,</hi> It was, was at the ſame Time with the <hi>White Throne,</hi> (as it were Blancking All into the High Spirituality of the Eternal State) and at the ſame Time, that there was <hi>no place Found for Them;</hi> and therefore for no other ſuch after them;and at the ſame Time, that <hi>John ſaw the Dead, Small and Great ſtand before God,</hi> and that <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hell,</hi> and <hi>whatever was not written in the Book of Life, were caſt into the Lake:</hi> This Conjunction of Theſe Things I am Aſſured none can deny, that ſhall but with the Leaſt obſervation Read <hi>Revel.</hi> 20. 11. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>If then <hi>Death,</hi> and <hi>Hell, were caſt into the Lake,</hi> then certainly <hi>Sathan,</hi> the <hi>Prince of the Power of Death,</hi> if <hi>whatever was not Written in the Book of Life,</hi> was <hi>caſt into the Lake,</hi> then certainly <hi>Sathan,</hi> for whom the <hi>Lake</hi> was prepar'd, muſt needs be at this Time <hi>Caſt into the Lake;</hi> But for what Reaſons the <hi>Beast</hi> and <hi>Falſe Prophet</hi> were there before Him, I have elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where declar'd.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Sathan</hi>'s <hi>caſting into the Lake</hi> muſt needs be after the <hi>Thouſand Years,</hi> as is expreſs, <hi>Revel.</hi> 20. 7. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and will be more argu'd immediately; if then the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that were in Being, when <hi>Sathan</hi> was <hi>caſt into the Lake,</hi> were the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that <hi>Fled from the White Throne,</hi> as is prov'd; It muſt needs be that <hi>Heaven,</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that were in Being after the <hi>Thouſand Years,</hi> that <hi>Fled.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>And if the <hi>Heaven,</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that Fled, were the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that were in Being at the <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> end, They muſt be the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that were in Being during the <hi>Thouſand Years;</hi> who can ſo much as Imagine other? And If They were the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> during the <hi>Thouſand Years,</hi> They muſt be the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> during the <hi>Holy City.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>For the <hi>City, cap.</hi> 20. and <hi>cap.</hi> 21. muſt needs be the <hi>City New Jeruſalem,</hi>
                     <pb n="3" facs="tcp:50119:5"/> which as call'd <hi>Holy, c.</hi> 21. So it was the <hi>Camp of the Saints,</hi> ſecur'd from <hi>Sathan</hi>'s Approach, during the <hi>Thouſand Years:</hi> And ſo <hi>Righteouſneſs dwelt in it, c.</hi> 20 9. And it is the <hi>Beloved City, c.</hi> 20. 9. Becauſe it is the <hi>Bride</hi> the <hi>Lamb</hi>'s <hi>Wife, c.</hi> 21. 9, 10.</p>
                  <p>Now this <hi>Beloved City,</hi> and <hi>Camp of the Saints,</hi> had had a State of <hi>Peace</hi> and <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> for a <hi>Thouſand Years,</hi> while <hi>Sathan was in Priſon,</hi> and <hi>Gog</hi> and <hi>Magog</hi> ſtir'd not; All which Time the <hi>Saints Above ſat on Thrones,</hi> and <hi>Reigned with Chriſt a Thouſand Years;</hi> and the <hi>Partakers</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurrection</hi> on <hi>Earth</hi> were <hi>Bleſſed,</hi> and <hi>Holy,</hi> and were <hi>Prieſts of God, and of Chriſt</hi> and <hi>Reigned with Him a Thouſand Years,</hi> and ſo were for ever <hi>Holy,</hi> and <hi>Bleſſed;</hi> For over ſuch, the <hi>Second Death hath no Power.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p>If then the <hi>Heaven,</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that were in Being during the <hi>Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Years</hi> of the <hi>Holy City,</hi> be the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that <hi>Fled,</hi> when <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>than was caſt into the Lake after the Thouſand Years,</hi> as hath been ſhown; Theſe muſt be the <hi>Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that <hi>John</hi> ſaw together with the <hi>Holy City;</hi> And ſo they muſt be the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and the <hi>New Earth</hi> that He <hi>ſaw, c.</hi> 21. 1. and not the <hi>Firſt;</hi> and there can be no more, except a <hi>New Creation</hi> be Piled on this <hi>New Creation,</hi> and <hi>New Heaven</hi> and <hi>Earth</hi> that <hi>Fled</hi> away: So They End with the 1000 <hi>Y.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="argument">
               <head>Argum. 2.</head>
               <p>If according to <hi>Prophecy,</hi> concerning the <hi>Thouſand Years Reign of Chriſt,</hi> with his <hi>Saints of the Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> and his <hi>Saints, Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers of the Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> There muſt by the <hi>Apoſtolical</hi> Plain Doctrine be a ſpace of Time between the Time of the <hi>Saints Dead</hi> in Chriſt, Riſing firſt, who Anſwer to the <hi>Saints</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection;</hi> and the <hi>Saints Chang'd,</hi> who Anſwer to the <hi>Partakers of the Firſt Reſurrection;</hi> and the Time of theſe <hi>Chang'd Saints</hi> being <hi>Caught up;</hi> This ſpace by <hi>Prophecy</hi> muſt be the <hi>Thouſand Years Reign of Chriſt</hi> with his <hi>Saints?</hi> But ſuch a ſpace will in the <hi>Apoſtles</hi> plain Doctrine be found; Therefore It muſt by <hi>Prophecy</hi> be the ſpace of the <hi>thouſand years;</hi> and ſo the <hi>thouſand years Kingdom of Christ</hi> will be Fully Aſſured from hence.</p>
               <p>If the <hi>Apoſtles</hi> plaſn Doctrine be, That there are two Sorts of Saints, and no more at the <hi>Reſurrection</hi> viz. The <hi>Saints Raiſed Incorruptible,</hi> and the <hi>Saints</hi> who ſhall not <hi>Sleep,</hi> but be <hi>Chang'd; Chang'd</hi> in oppoſition to <hi>Dying,</hi> farr below the priviledge of being <hi>Chang'd; Chang'd</hi> in diſtinction from being <hi>Rais'd Incorruptible,</hi> a priviledge above being <hi>Changed,</hi> when Incor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruptible is not Added, And if theſe make up the <hi>We All</hi> of Saints, even The <hi>Living, The Remaining</hi> Reſcued from the <hi>perdition</hi> of the <hi>Wicked Dead,</hi> and preſerved under Guards of Life, Then Theſe are two Sorts of Saints, vix. Principals in the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> and <hi>Partakers</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection;</hi> Seeing To be the <hi>We All</hi> is to be Saints or <hi>Holy:</hi> To be <hi>the Living</hi> is to be <hi>Partakers,</hi> To be <hi>Chang'd</hi> but not Incorruptible is to be no more than <hi>Partakers;</hi> To be <hi>Hi Zontes,</hi> The <hi>Living, Hi Perilipomeni,</hi> or the <hi>Preſerved</hi> is to be <hi>Bleſſed,</hi> For over <hi>Such the ſecond Death hath no power.</hi> But All Theſe Things are expreſsly written. 1. <hi>Cor.</hi> 15. 51, 52. 1. <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 4 14 &amp;c. and <hi>Revel.</hi> 20. 4, 5, 6. And Both theſe Sorts of Saints <hi>Live</hi> and <hi>Reign with Chriſt a thouſand years:</hi> So There is a <hi>thouſand years Kingdom.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>2. If the <hi>Saints,</hi> The <hi>Living,</hi> the <hi>Remaining,</hi> who <hi>dye not,</hi> but are <hi>Chang'd,</hi> are <hi>Chang'd</hi> in the Atom of Time, the very ſame <hi>Moment</hi> in
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:50119:6"/> the very <hi>Twinckle of an Eye</hi> with the <hi>Saints Raiſed,</hi> 1 Cor. 15. 51, 52. and yet The <hi>Saints Dead in Chriſt Riſe Firſt,</hi> and the <hi>Saints, The Living,</hi> and <hi>the Remaining</hi> are not <hi>Caught up</hi> till an <hi>Epita</hi> (not to be Tranſlated [Then] but [Afterwards] which <hi>Epita</hi> is ſo Tranſlated [<hi>Afterward</hi>] 1 Cor. 15. 23. and leaves Room to almoſt 1700 Y. ſince Chriſts <hi>Reſurrection;</hi> If All This be, Then there may be ſuch a ſpace as the 1000 Y. from the <hi>Raiſing</hi> the <hi>Dead</hi> Saints, <hi>Changing</hi> the <hi>living Saints;</hi> before The <hi>living, The Remaining Saints are Caught up:</hi> and the <hi>Ama</hi> Tranſlated [<hi>Together</hi>] ſhall not ſignify <hi>Toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther</hi> in Time, but <hi>pariter,</hi> or Alike, (as it muſt needs be <hi>Rom.</hi> 3. 12.) with the <hi>Dead Saints raiſed,</hi> and with Chriſt <hi>Above,</hi> (who cannot be ſay'd to be <note place="margin">
                     <hi>1 Theſſ.</hi> 5. 10. and elſewhere</note> 
                  <hi>Caught up</hi> at all; For <hi>Chriſt Brings Them with Him,</hi>) much leſſe, <hi>Together,</hi> with the <hi>Saints Riſing,</hi> For this would Contradict the <hi>Apoſtles Proton,</hi> or <hi>Firſt,</hi> of the <hi>Saints riſing;</hi> and his <hi>Epita,</hi> or <hi>Afterward,</hi> of the <hi>Living Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining Saints caught up.</hi> All this we find expreſs. 1 <hi>Theſ.</hi> 4. 14. <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Seeing then by the Apoſt. a Space there muſt be, and <hi>Prophecy</hi> ſays ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſly, the <hi>Dead Saints, Living</hi> and <hi>Reigning</hi> with Chriſt <hi>on Thrones</hi> a 1000 Y. was the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> and that the <hi>Reign</hi> of the <hi>Partakers</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection, Bleſſed</hi> and <hi>Holy,</hi> and on whom the <hi>Second Death hath no Power,</hi> is a <hi>Reign with Chriſt</hi> alſo of a 1000 Y. It muſt be a 1000 Y; So Chriſt muſt needs have a <hi>Kingdom</hi> of a 1000 Years.</p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="argument">
               <head>Argum. 3d.</head>
               <p>If the <hi>Saints Raiſed Sitt</hi> on <hi>Thrones with Chriſt,</hi> as above, a 1000 Y. and There is a <hi>City</hi> and <hi>Cittadell of Saints on Earth</hi> for a 1000 Y. and who after are made <hi>to Sitt on Chriſt's Throne,</hi> in his Kingdom, ere the end, according to <hi>Prophecy;</hi> and that According to the <hi>Apoſtle; The Saints chang'd, The living</hi> and <hi>The Remaining</hi> are on Earth, while <hi>Chriſt,</hi> and the <hi>Raiſed Saints</hi> are above; and this for ſome ſpace of Time; Then how clear a proof is there of the 1000 <hi>Years Kingdom of Chriſt</hi> in the <hi>New Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven</hi> Inhabited by the raiſed Saints, and in the New Earth, Inhabited by the <hi>riſing Remaining Saints?</hi> But ſo it is according to the <hi>Prophecy,</hi> and Doctrine of Scriptures, Such a <hi>Kingdom</hi> therefore There ſhall be.</p>
               <p n="1">1. It is never ſaid in Scripture, <hi>Chriſt ſhall come down on Earth,</hi> at his <hi>ſecond Coming;</hi> But He is the <hi>Epouranios,</hi> the <hi>Lord from Heaven;</hi> The <hi>Heavenly;</hi> not <hi>Earthy,</hi> as the <hi>Firſt Adam,</hi> As He <hi>went up to Heaven in a Cloud,</hi> ſo He ſhall be ſeen <hi>Coming in a Cloud;</hi> Then indeed <hi>out of ſight;</hi> But now <hi>Every Eye ſhall ſee him,</hi> as Above, Thoſe places, <hi>Job.</hi> 19. 25. <hi>Zech.</hi> 14. 4. that ſeem to Favour Chriſts <hi>ſtanding upon the Earth</hi> at the laſt day; The <hi>Hebrew</hi> Word may better be Tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſlated <hi>Above the Earth,</hi> or <hi>Over</hi> it, He indeed <hi>Deſcends</hi> into the <hi>Lower Heaven;</hi> His Glory as the Sun's Reaching down to the <hi>Earth;</hi> ſo This, 1 <hi>Theſſ</hi> 4. 17. Repreſents Him in the <hi>Clouds,</hi> and in the <hi>Air,</hi> where his <hi>Throne</hi> and <hi>Tribunal</hi> muſt needs then be.</p>
               <p n="2">2. The <hi>Raiſed Saints</hi> are there with Him, ſhining as the <hi>Firmament,</hi> and as the <hi>Stars,</hi> even as the <hi>Sun, Reigning with Him in the Air, viz.</hi> the <hi>New Heaven</hi> above, a 1000 <hi>Y.</hi> as <hi>Ana</hi> in <hi>Ana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaſis</hi> may well ſignifie.</p>
               <p n="3">3. The <hi>Living,</hi> and the <hi>Remaining Saints,</hi> as the <hi>Kings of the Earth,</hi> the <hi>Nations</hi> of the <hi>Saved,</hi> walking in the <hi>Light</hi> of, and <hi>Bringing their Glory to the Jeruſalem</hi> Above, <hi>Healed with the Leaves of the Tree of Life, Reign in the Beloved City,</hi> and in the <hi>Cittadel</hi> of the <hi>Saints,</hi> as with Chriſt always in their Eye a 1000 <hi>Y.</hi> and at laſt are <hi>Caught up to Chriſt</hi> in the <hi>Air,</hi> into a Like State with the <hi>Sts.</hi> Above, and are made to <hi>ſit down on his Throne</hi> in His <hi>Kingdom</hi> Above, where He <hi>Reſides</hi> the 1000 <hi>Y.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And thus the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and the <hi>New Earth</hi> are Inhabited, during the <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> according to both <hi>Apoſtolic</hi> Doctrine, and <hi>Prophecy.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>When at the End Theſe <hi>Living Remaining Saints</hi> are <hi>Caught up.</hi> Then They put on perfect <hi>Incorruption</hi> and <hi>Immortality;</hi> and the Triumphal <hi>Song</hi> over <hi>Death</hi> is Sung. For it is <hi>Swallowed up in Victory; Sathan,</hi> the <hi>Dead,</hi> and <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hell,</hi> who had been Condemned to <hi>Lye as the Footſtool of Chriſt</hi>'s <hi>Feet</hi> at the Beginning of the 1000 <hi>Y.</hi> are now <hi>caſt into the Lake,</hi> ſo the <hi>Laſt Enemy Death</hi> is <hi>Brought to Nought;</hi> The <hi>Kingdom</hi> in a General <hi>Rendezvouz,</hi> or <hi>Meeting</hi> of <hi>Saints,</hi> ſpoken of alſo, 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 4. 17. is <hi>deliver'd up</hi> to God, and the <hi>Father All in All;</hi> and ſo All <hi>Saints</hi> are <hi>Outo,</hi> in that very Poſture and State of that Meeting, <hi>Ever with the Lord,</hi> with God, and with Chriſt.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:50119:7"/>
            <head>A Continuation of Arguments from the <hi>Spirits Speaking <gap reason="foreign">
                     <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
                  </gap>,</hi> expreſly in <hi>Scriptures,</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Dead, and of <hi>Gog</hi> and <hi>Magog,</hi> by way of Further Illuſtration of the 1000 Years <hi>Kingdom.</hi>
            </head>
            <div n="4" type="argument">
               <head>Arg. 4.</head>
               <p>IF it be declar'd in Plain Scripture, that the <hi>Seed of the Woman ſhall Break the Serpent's Head,</hi> as <hi>Gen.</hi> 3. 15. and that <hi>God will Bruiſe</hi> Sathan <hi>under the Saints Feet ſhortly, Rom.</hi> 16. 20. and that moſt Expreſs <hi>Prophetic Scripture</hi> tells us, that during the 1000 Years, wherein <hi>Chriſt Reigns with his Dead Saints Rais'd, Living,</hi> and <hi>Sitting on Thrones;</hi> and with his <hi>Saints, Partakers of the First Reſurrection; Sathan lyes Chain'd, Seal'd, Bound,</hi> and <hi>Impriſon'd</hi> for all that 1000 Years; All which, ſo many, and ſo Emphatical Expreſſions ſpeake the utter Impoſſibility of his <hi>Annoying the Holy City</hi> for that 1000 Years; If All this be, It is then certain, that Chriſt, as He ſhall Appear the Glorious <hi>Second Adam,</hi> the <hi>Seed of the Woman,</hi> and the <hi>Lord from Heaven</hi> alſo, hath a <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom</hi> of a 1000 Years; wherein as Referring to that Promiſe, <hi>Sathan,</hi> Call'd Remarkably the <hi>Old Serpent, Rev</hi> 20. 1. Lyes under Him with his <hi>Head Broken</hi> by Him; and that in this <hi>Kingdom,</hi> Coming according to the <hi>Apocalyptic</hi> Phraſe, <gap reason="foreign">
                     <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>Quickly,</hi> God <hi>Bruiſes Sathan</hi> under the <hi>Saints Feet,</hi> who <hi>Reign</hi> while He is ſo <hi>Bound,</hi> and <hi>Impriſon'd</hi> theſe 1000 Years alſo.</p>
               <p>Now that which Juſtifies the moſt Solid, and Subſtantial Senſe of <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>than</hi>'s <hi>Binding,</hi> and for a 1000 Years, under an utter Impoſſibility of <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noying the Divine Kingdom</hi> for thoſe 1000 Years, is; That Both the <hi>Bind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> and the 1000 Years, muſt Bear a proportion to the <hi>Looſing Sathan</hi> for a <hi>Little Seaſon</hi> after the 1000 Years Expir'd, and to the <hi>Caſting Sathan into the Lake;</hi> which muſt needs ſignifie an utter Impoſſibility of his Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, except as within his own <hi>Lake,</hi> againſt the <hi>Divine Kingdom</hi> for ever; as All muſt needs Acknowledge; If then the <hi>Binding: Chaining, Impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Sealing Sathan</hi> in ſuch an <hi>Impriſonment</hi> for a 1000 Years, Bear a pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion to the <hi>Caſting Sathan into the Lake,</hi> He muſt be under an utter Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſibility of Acting againſt the <hi>Beloved City,</hi> and <hi>Camp of the Saints,</hi> or the <hi>Divine Kingdom</hi> for that 1000 Years, as He ſhall be, when in the <hi>Lake to Eternity;</hi> And if the 1000 Year Bear a proportion to the <hi>Little Seaſon</hi> of his being <hi>Looſed</hi> after Them, then that <hi>Little Seaſon</hi> muſt be but a Little part of a 1000 Years.</p>
               <p>Now who can ſay? There hath been ever yet ſuch an Efficacious Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prizal of the Action of <hi>Sathan</hi> againſt the <hi>Beloved City,</hi> and <hi>Camp of the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:50119:8"/> Saints,</hi> as will Agree with the <hi>Seed of the Woman, Breaking his Head,</hi> or <hi>God Bruiſing Sathan</hi> under the <hi>Feet of the Saints</hi> ſhortly, or with his <hi>Chain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Impriſoning,</hi> or <hi>Sealing,</hi> ſo as to Bear a Proportion to his <hi>caſting into the Lake?</hi> Or how can the Time, <hi>viz.</hi> from <hi>Conſtantine,</hi> Generally pitch'd upon for the 1000 Years, be that Time? wherein Both <hi>Antichrist,</hi> and <hi>Mahomet,</hi> have Rag'd ſo againſt the <hi>Church of Chriſt;</hi> And how could the Time ſince thoſe 1000 Years ended, <hi>viz.</hi> about 1300 A. D. be without Great unreaſonableneſs, call'd the Time of <hi>Sathan</hi>'s <hi>Looſing,</hi> which hath been the very Time of the <hi>Goſpel</hi> Riſing out of the <hi>Apoſtaſie,</hi> firſt in the <hi>Bohemian Teſtimony,</hi> and ſince by the <hi>Reformation!</hi> How can it be call'd a <hi>Little Time,</hi> compar'd with the 1000 Years? when it is almoſt Half a 1000 Years already; beſides what may be expected of ſuch a State, as the preſent is; according to ſuch Apprehenſions, as Give no Credit to the Aſſigning of any Time according to <hi>Prophecy,</hi> that might be ſhort.</p>
               <p>I Appeal therefore to Any Conſidering Perſon, whether this be not E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qual to the <hi>Spirit</hi>'s <hi>ſpeaking expreſly,</hi> when by plain, and <hi>Prophetic Scripture</hi> com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd; Chriſt ſhall have a <hi>Kingdom</hi> of a 1000 Years, which is yet to come; and that after the End of that 1000 Years <hi>Kingdom,</hi> within a very <hi>Little Time,</hi> how <hi>Little</hi> we can't expreſs, ſeeing <hi>Scripture</hi> hath not, <hi>Sathan</hi> ſhall for ever be <hi>Thrown into the Lake.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="5" type="argument">
               <head>Argum. 5.</head>
               <p>If there be a State of the <hi>Wicked, Dead</hi> before the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> and <hi>Deſtroyed</hi> by the <hi>Fire of his Coming;</hi> and yet Rais'd to a State of ſuffering, that according to plain <hi>Doctrinal Scripture,</hi> may be a 1000 Y. and according to <hi>Prophetic Scripture</hi> muſt be a 1000 Years, and then the <hi>Lake;</hi> Then It is certain, There is ſuch a 1000 Years <hi>Kingdom of Christ.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>1. If according to both ſorts of <hi>Scripture,</hi> There muſt be a <hi>Riſing</hi> of the <hi>Wicked,</hi> or <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>njuſt,</hi> that have <hi>done Evil</hi> at the very ſame Time, that the <hi>Just,</hi> and that They that have <hi>done well,</hi> Ariſe, and in Conjunction with Them; and that They with Them ſhall make an <hi>Appearance</hi> before the <hi>Tribunal of Chriſt;</hi> Then that muſt be in ſome State, and for ſome Time, or ſpace of Time, whatever State, or Space that ſhall be; And ſeeing the <hi>Juſt Ariſe at the Coming of Chriſt,</hi> and at his <hi>Kingdom</hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15. 23. The <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>njuſt</hi> muſt then <hi>Ariſe</hi> alſo; This being a General Principle, and Article of Faith, I only Refer to the Scriptures, moſt Evidently proving it. <hi>Eccleſ.</hi> 12. 14. <hi>Dan.</hi> 12. 2. <hi>John</hi> 5. 29. <hi>Acts</hi> 24. 15. <hi>Mat.</hi> 25. 31. 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 5. 10. <hi>Revel.</hi> 11 18.</p>
               <p>And according to my Judgment, when by the <hi>Sixth Voice, Rev</hi> 14. 18. (For there had been Five before it;) The <hi>Earth</hi> is <hi>Reap'd</hi> by Him, that had on his <hi>Head</hi> the <hi>Golden Crown</hi> in the <hi>Raiſing</hi> the <hi>Dead Saints,</hi> and <hi>Chang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> the <hi>Living;</hi> In the <hi>Seventh Voice,</hi> (by which <hi>Seven Voices</hi> in that Chap. I underſtand the <hi>Seven Thunders</hi> open'd) the <hi>Cluſters of the Vine of the Earth are Gather'd,</hi> and <hi>Thrown into the Wine-preſs of the Wrath of God;</hi> that is; The <hi>Wicked</hi> are <hi>Raiſed</hi> to <hi>Condemnation,</hi> and to <hi>Everlaſting puniſhment;</hi> which by Comparing <hi>Rev.</hi> 16. 14. and <hi>c.</hi> 19. 10. 15. is done at the <hi>Bat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tel of Armageddon,</hi> when Chriſt with the <hi>Armies of Heaven, viz.</hi> the <hi>Raiſed Saints on White Horſes in Linnen, White</hi> and <hi>Clean,</hi> expreſſing the Purity of
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:50119:9"/> 
                  <hi>Spiritual Bodies</hi> of the <hi>Reſurrection, Following Him,</hi> in <hi>Righteouſneſs Judgeth,</hi> and <hi>maketh War on all the Wicked,</hi> and <hi>Treadeth the Wine-preſs of the Wrath of God,</hi> into which <hi>They are caſt.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And yet Becauſe the <hi>Wicked Riſe</hi> thus to <hi>Shame,</hi> and to <hi>Contempt,</hi> and to this <hi>Everlaſting Puniſhment,</hi> their <hi>Reſurrection</hi> is Counted, as no <hi>Reſurre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction;</hi> neither in <hi>Doctrinal,</hi> nor in <hi>Prophetic Scripture:</hi> The <hi>Reſurrection</hi> Abſolutely ſpoken of, is by our Lord ſtyl'd; The <hi>Reſurrection of the Juſt, Luke</hi> 14 14. and <hi>c.</hi> 20. 36. The <hi>Children of God</hi> are only Accounted the <hi>Children of the Reſurrection:</hi> The Apoſtle <hi>Paul</hi> in thoſe Two Great Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſes of the <hi>Reſurrection,</hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15. and 1 <hi>Theſſ</hi> 4. 13. ſo Frames the Doctrine of it, as to Apply it only to the <hi>Saints,</hi> who are <hi>Chriſts at his Coming,</hi> and to the <hi>We All of the Saints Changed, v.</hi> 23. <hi>v.</hi> 51. 52. and to Thoſe whoſe who <hi>Sleep in,</hi> or <hi>through Jeſus,</hi> Riſing firſt, and to the <hi>Liv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> the <hi>Remaining,</hi> who are <hi>Chang<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d</hi> in the ſame <hi>Moment</hi> with the <hi>Saints Rais'd;</hi> afterward, <hi>viz.</hi> the 1000 Years after, <hi>Caught</hi> up to Them, and into a Like State with Them, 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 4. 13. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſo the Apoſtle Leaves the <hi>Wicked</hi> wholly out in Both.</p>
               <p>Agreeably <hi>Prophecy,</hi> as if They were not <hi>Rais'd,</hi> calls the <hi>Remnant, Slain with the Sword of Him that Sat on the Horſe,</hi> Rev. 19. 21. as in that very word, the <hi>Reſt,</hi> or <hi>Remnant,</hi> (and in the ſame Senſe with <hi>Slain</hi>) of the <hi>Dead, c.</hi> 20: 5. <hi>viz.</hi> The <hi>Remnant,</hi> or <hi>Reſt,</hi> becauſe not <hi>caſt into the Lake,</hi> as the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and <hi>Falſe Prophet,</hi> but only <hi>Slain;</hi> The <hi>Dead,</hi> becauſe <hi>Slain,</hi> and neither Saints of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> nor <hi>Saints Partakers</hi> of it; Both which <hi>Lived,</hi> and <hi>Reigned</hi> with Chriſt a 1000 Years; But the <hi>Dead Liv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed</hi> not for the 1000 Years, that the <hi>Saints Reigned;</hi> and yet to ſhew They were an Appendage to the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection</hi> as Rais'd, though but to Death; till They were nam'd, It is not ſaid, <hi>This is the Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> Then it is, and They are ſet in the middle of both ſorts of <hi>Saints;</hi> What Greater Evidence can there be of the 1000 Years <hi>Kingdom,</hi> then the plain Scriptures, Leaving the <hi>Wicked</hi> out of the High Diſcourſes of the <hi>Reſurrection,</hi> and <hi>Prophecy</hi> in Agreement, calling them the <hi>Dead,</hi> as nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Principals, nor <hi>Partakers</hi> of the <hi>First Reſurrection,</hi> but Aſſigning one and the ſame 1000 Years, to the State of the Principals, to the State of the <hi>Dead not Living,</hi> and to the <hi>Partakers</hi> in the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> and the <hi>Reign with Chriſt</hi> Concurrent with it!</p>
            </div>
            <div n="6" type="argument">
               <head>Argum. 6.</head>
               <p>If <hi>Gog</hi> and <hi>Magog</hi> can by Scripture be Cleared to be theſe ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry <hi>Dead, ſlain</hi> with the <hi>Sword of Chriſt's Mouth,</hi> and ſo in the State of the <hi>Dead</hi> the 1000 Years, and then making their laſt Attempt, and ſo <hi>caſt in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Lake;</hi> This will ſtill Compleat the proof of the 1000 Years <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom;</hi> But there will be Found a <hi>Cloud</hi> of both <hi>Witneſſes, Prophetical</hi> and <hi>Doctrinal</hi> Scripture Probabilities; and one Great Proof of Scripture <hi>Doctrinal,</hi> and <hi>Prophetical</hi> Compar'd, that will conclude, it muſt be ſo.</p>
               <p>Let then the Scripture Correſpondencies, both <hi>Prophetical</hi> firſt, to which this Figure firſt belongs, and then the <hi>Doctrinal</hi> be juſt nam'd, as Probabilities, and then the more concluſive Argument weigh'd. The
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:50119:10"/> Firſt Rudiments of this Image are Found in <hi>Ezekiel,</hi> which, whatever Litteral Senſe it may have, ſerves this <hi>Apocalyptical</hi> Image, with theſe Great Correſpondencies: 1. <hi>Gog Magog</hi> is a Confluence of Nations: 2. They Appear in <hi>Battel:</hi> 3. They come up againſt a <hi>People Reſcued from the Sword,</hi> and of <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nwall<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d Villages:</hi> 4. The <hi>Vengeance</hi> and <hi>Fury of God comes up as in his Face upon Them:</hi> 5. Their <hi>Death,</hi> and <hi>Graves</hi> are made moſt Monumental. <hi>Ezek. c.</hi> 38. <hi>c</hi> 39. Proportionably in the <hi>Revelation;</hi> Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though Their Name is Conceal'd in the Firſt; Yet I lay their Appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance both in the <hi>Battle of Armageddon, c.</hi> 6. 14. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and in this <hi>Battle,</hi> where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in They are named, <hi>c.</hi> 20. 8 <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſo firſt they are a confluence of <hi>Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,</hi> the <hi>Kings,</hi> and the whole <hi>World, c.</hi> 16. <hi>Kings, Captains</hi> Great Small, <hi>c.</hi> 19. 18. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Gather'd under the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and <hi>Falſe Prophet</hi> Both, and under the <hi>Dragon,</hi> by <hi>Spirits of Devils, c.</hi> 16. But when the <hi>Beaſt</hi> and <hi>Falſe Prophet</hi> were <hi>caſt into the Lake, c.</hi> 19. They are Rallied under the <hi>Dragon, Sathan</hi> only, <hi>c.</hi> 20. and their Number, to ſhew their Confluence is as the <hi>Sand of the Sea;</hi> Their City being a <hi>Hammonah,</hi> as <hi>Ezek.</hi> 39. 16. 2. Their Appearing in <hi>Battle</hi> is plain, and it is their Appearance under the mighty Efficacy of <hi>Spirits</hi> of <hi>Devils,</hi> or <hi>Sathan,</hi> in all their Malice againſt the <hi>Divine Kingdom.</hi> 3. They come againſt the <hi>Kings of the Eaſt, viz.</hi> (as I underſtand) the <hi>Saints,</hi> the <hi>Living,</hi> the <hi>Remaining, Reſcued from the Sword of Him that ſat on the Horſe,</hi> and on <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nwalled Cities, viz.</hi> theſe <hi>Saints,</hi> before the <hi>New Jeruſalem came down,</hi> and now again after the 1000 Years, when the <hi>New Jeruſalems</hi> Glory, as <hi>Walls</hi> and <hi>Bulwarks of Salva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> was Retir'd. 4. The <hi>Vengeance of God</hi> is alike deſcrib'd every where, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 38. 21. <hi>&amp;c. Sword, Fire,</hi> and <hi>Hail, Rev. c.</hi> 16. <hi>c</hi> 19. <hi>Fire, c.</hi> 20. 5. 9. As their <hi>Graves</hi> in their <hi>Hamon-Gog,</hi> and <hi>Hammonah,</hi> are <hi>Ezek.</hi> 39. ſo Their being <hi>Slain,</hi> call<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d the <hi>Dead, caſt into the Lake,</hi> is in the <hi>Revelation</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Correſpondencies of <hi>Doctrinal,</hi> and <hi>Prophetic</hi> Scripture Inducing a probability, that <hi>Gog Magog</hi> are the <hi>Wicked rais<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d,</hi> are, that there is a diſtance of Time between the <hi>Enemies of Chriſt,</hi> being <hi>made his Footſtool,</hi> and their being Finally <hi>deſtroy'd:</hi> The <hi>Man of ſin</hi> made up of the <hi>Beaſt,</hi> and <hi>Falſe Praphet,</hi> 2 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 2. 3. <hi>Rev</hi> 17. 8. 11. <hi>c.</hi> 19. 21 goes firſt into <hi>Perdition,</hi> and is <hi>caſt into the Lake</hi> at Chriſt's very <hi>Appearance,</hi> no <hi>Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chriſtian Church,</hi> or <hi>Kingdom</hi> being any more poſſible; But the Three other Great <hi>Enemies of Chriſt, Sathan, Wicked Men, Hell</hi> and <hi>Death</hi> are firſt the <hi>Footſtool of Chriſt,</hi> according to <hi>Pſal.</hi> 110. <hi>Heb.</hi> 1 13. <hi>c.</hi> 10. 13. All <hi>Rule, Authority</hi> and <hi>Power</hi> are not Finally <hi>deſtroy'd,</hi> or under the <hi>Catargeſis,</hi> till the very <hi>End; Death</hi> is the <hi>Laſt Enemy,</hi> ſo <hi>deſtroyed</hi> juſt before the <hi>Kingdom Given up,</hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15. 24, 26. And the very date of this Time is, when the <hi>We of All of Saints,</hi> the <hi>Living,</hi> the <hi>Remaining</hi> are <hi>caught up</hi> to Chriſt into a like State with the <hi>Saints raiſed Firſt</hi> with Him in the <hi>Clouds,</hi> and ſo put on Abſolute <hi>Immortality,</hi> and <hi>Incorruption;</hi> Then the Triumphal Song over <hi>Dearh</hi> is ſung; and ſo All <hi>Saints are ever with the Lord in the Clouds,</hi> or <hi>Air of the New Heaven,</hi> and in the <hi>Kingdom deliver'd up to God All in All.</hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15. 51. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 4. 13. The Occaſion of the Great
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:50119:11"/> Miſtake in this matier is, that the <hi>Changing,</hi> and the being <hi>caught up,</hi> are not diſtinguiſh'd; The <hi>changing into Bodies of Paradiſe,</hi> or of a <hi>Participation</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> is indeed at the ſame Moment with the <hi>Saints riſing Firſt;</hi> There is an <hi>Epita,</hi> an Afterward of a 1000 Years, before They are <hi>caught up.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>According to this, The <hi>Enemies of Chriſt,</hi> as the <hi>Footſtool of his Feet,</hi> Bear up the State of his <hi>Sitting on the Throne</hi> for the 1000 Years, <hi>viz. Sathan Chain'd, Bonnd, Impriſon'd,</hi> and <hi>Seal'd up.</hi> The <hi>Wicked,</hi> as <hi>Gog Magog</hi> in ſuch an Infinite Number, Exil'd in the <hi>Four corners of the New Earth,</hi> Appear, but cannot ſtir againſt the <hi>Beloved City,</hi> and <hi>Camp of the Saints</hi> for the 1000 Years: <hi>Death,</hi> as not <hi>caſt into the Lake,</hi> hath an Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearance, and <hi>a</hi> poſſibility of Action, in that the <hi>Living Remaining Saints,</hi> in having but a <hi>part,</hi> and not the Full yet in the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> have not put on <hi>Immortality</hi> and <hi>Incorruption;</hi> yet ſo <hi>Heal'd with the Leaves of the Tree of Life,</hi> They ſhall not <hi>dye; Death</hi> cannot Faſten, though It ſhews its Fangs. When Chriſt does, as it were, Take off his <hi>Feet from his Footſtool;</hi> from all his Three <hi>Enemies,</hi> in order to Give up the <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi> They Every one Riſe, as into Action; <hi>Sathan</hi> the Prince, the <hi>Gog Magog,</hi> the <hi>Dead</hi> under Him, <hi>viz.</hi> Condemn'd, and ſo in the State of <hi>Death;</hi> and <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hell</hi> under their Prince; All theſe move to their utmoſt Activity againſt the <hi>Holy City,</hi> but as in Anticipation to the <hi>Lake,</hi> or a preſent Deſcription of it, <hi>Fire comes down from Heaven; Sathan</hi> long ago Condemn'd is without any New Judgment <hi>caſt into the Lake:</hi> The Judgment of <hi>Gog Magog</hi> the <hi>Dead,</hi> from all the Receptacles of <hi>Death,</hi> is Recollected, and Ratified in their being All <hi>Judg<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d:</hi> And <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hell</hi> are <hi>caſt into the Lake</hi> with Them. This is the Final <hi>Catargeſts, deſtroying,</hi> and <hi>putting All the Enemies of Chriſt,</hi> that had been his <hi>Footſtool</hi> the 1000 Y. quite Below <hi>under his Feet.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Concluſive Argument from the Compare of <hi>Doctrinal</hi> and <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phetical</hi> Scripture, That <hi>Gog Magog are the wicked dead rais'd,</hi> is this; Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to all Scripture, the <hi>Wicked</hi> are Rais'd with the <hi>Servants of Chriſt,</hi> all at a Time; The <hi>Reſurrection</hi> is yet peculiar to the <hi>Saints,</hi> Becauſe the <hi>Wicked</hi> are Rais'd to <hi>Condemnation,</hi> and ſo to <hi>Death.</hi> All <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ngodly Men,</hi> whether Dead before, or Found Alive at Chriſt's Coming, are under the <hi>Perdition of the Fire of the Day of Judgment,</hi> and of <hi>Chriſt's coming;</hi> accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Apoſtle <hi>Peter, Ep.</hi> 2. <hi>c.</hi> 37. according to the Apoſtle <hi>Paul,</hi> 2 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 1. 8. and ſo There are none, The <hi>Living,</hi> The <hi>Remaining,</hi> but <hi>Saints.</hi> Then according to <hi>Prophecy,</hi> whatever is not Partaker of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> to which, nothing is Second, but the <hi>Second death,</hi> muſt be under that <hi>Second Death,</hi> Beginning with that very <hi>Firſt Reſurrection;</hi> ſo the <hi>Wicked dead rais'd,</hi> not partaking of that <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> Immediately Begin to have their <hi>part</hi> in the <hi>Lake,</hi> which is the <hi>Second death,</hi> though not <hi>caſt into it, Revel.</hi> 21. 8. as the <hi>Living Saints</hi> in the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> though not <hi>caught up</hi> into it; <hi>Gog Magog</hi> then call'd the <hi>Nations,</hi> and in ſo vaſt a <hi>Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber as the Sand of the Sea,</hi> muſt be the <hi>Dead,</hi> having their part, though
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:50119:12" rendition="simple:additions"/> not the <hi>full</hi> in the <hi>Lake;</hi> For there are no <hi>Earth</hi> none elſe but the <hi>Nations of the ſaved;</hi> But <hi>Gog</hi> does not for the 1000 Years Annoy the <hi>Holy City,</hi> being Exil'd in the <hi>Four corners,</hi> even as the <hi>Wine-preſs</hi> is <hi>Trod</hi> 1600 <hi>Furlongs</hi> without the <hi>Holy City,</hi> or <hi>Camp;</hi> ſhewing the <hi>Four ſquare Vengenance,</hi> Iſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from the <hi>Four ſquare Holy City,</hi> on the Wicked without it, The <hi>Saints</hi> above Equal to <hi>Angels,</hi> with the <hi>Lamb,</hi> Behold their <hi>Torment,</hi> and are <hi>Satisfied with their Fleſh,</hi> viz. <hi>Rejoyce in the Vengeance;</hi> The <hi>Saints</hi> below, as it were <hi>Burying Gog, Ez.</hi> 39. 11, 12. in <hi>Iſrael,</hi> nigh the <hi>Holy City,</hi> go out to Behold their <hi>Carcaſes;</hi> For without are Thoſe <hi>Dogs, Going round about this City, Eſay.</hi> 66. 24. <hi>Pſal.</hi> 59 14. <hi>Rev.</hi> 14. 20. <hi>c.</hi> 22. 15.</p>
               <p>Concerning the <hi>Gog Magog,</hi> as the <hi>Dead Rais'd to Comdemnation,</hi> I have this Remarquable to Add, that when at the Final Doom, They are ſaid to <hi>ſtand before God, Rev.</hi> 20. 21. The <hi>Earth</hi> is not ſaid to <hi>Give up any Dead.</hi> The <hi>Sea</hi> had (as <hi>Grotius</hi> and <hi>Piſcator</hi> Render it) <hi>Given up its Dead</hi> long before, <hi>viz.</hi> at the Beginning of the 1000 Years; when, as hath been prov'd, the <hi>New Heaven</hi> and <hi>New Earth</hi> entred, and There was <hi>no more Sea:</hi> Why then does not the <hi>Earth give up its Dead,</hi> as well as the <hi>Sea? viz.</hi> Becauſe the <hi>Sea</hi> giving up its <hi>Dead,</hi> wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> the <hi>Old Earth Burnt,</hi> became in its <hi>Four corners</hi> The Common <hi>Death,</hi> or State of the <hi>Dead,</hi> and the <hi>Hades,</hi> or <hi>Hell</hi> of Them: So <hi>Hades,</hi> or <hi>Hell,</hi> and <hi>Death</hi> Alone, Give<gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> up the <hi>Dead,</hi> and are <hi>caſt with Them into the Lake.</hi> This Aſſures, <hi>Earth</hi> is not meant by <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hades;</hi> except the <hi>Old,</hi> as <hi>Burnt,</hi> and Becoming the Seat of the <hi>Dead,</hi> and ſo <hi>caſt into one Common Lake:</hi> For when <hi>Gog</hi> came on the <hi>New Earth</hi> to Cover it, <hi>Fire from Heaven</hi> then Reſcued that <hi>Earth,</hi> and <hi>devour'd</hi> Them; So <hi>Death</hi> and <hi>Hades,</hi> or <hi>Hell,</hi> had all the <hi>Dead,</hi> for the <hi>Sea</hi> had before Given up its <hi>Dead</hi> to that <hi>Hades, Death</hi> and <hi>Hell,</hi> which is the <hi>Hamon Gog,</hi> or <hi>Hammonah</hi> of <hi>Gog Magog, Slain,</hi> and <hi>Buried</hi> in <hi>Iſrael, viz.</hi> without the <hi>Gate,</hi> and <hi>Camp</hi> of the <hi>Holy City,</hi> as <hi>Malefactors of Old: Sathan,</hi> for whom the <hi>Lake</hi> was firſt prepar'd, is <hi>caſt into it,</hi> without the Formality of a <hi>Judgment,</hi> as to his own place; The <hi>Dead;</hi> on whom the <hi>Judgment</hi> was at the 1000 Years Begun, is at their end Compleated. The <hi>New Jeruſalem, Seated</hi> in the <hi>New Heaven,</hi> and <hi>New Earth,</hi> upon their <hi>Flying,</hi> Re-Aſcends to God, from whom it Deſcended; So the <hi>Kingdom is deliver'd up to God All in All,</hi> and the <hi>Saints</hi> are for ever with the <hi>Lord,</hi> with God in Chriſt.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:50119:13"/>
            <head>A SUMMARY Of <hi>Arguments</hi> for the 1000 <hi>Y. Kingdom:</hi> By <hi>T. B.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <label>Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment 1.</label> IF the <hi>New Heaven</hi> and the <hi>New Earth</hi> be a Palace for <hi>Chriſt,</hi> the <hi>King</hi> of <hi>Glory,</hi> and for his <hi>Saints</hi> in <hi>Glory</hi> with <hi>Him;</hi> Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning with the <hi>Thouſand Years,</hi> and <hi>Flying away</hi> within a <hi>Little ſpace,</hi> after They are <hi>Ended;</hi> when the <hi>Kingdom</hi> is <hi>Delivered up,</hi> and the <hi>New Jeruſalem</hi> Re-aſcends to <hi>God;</hi> Then there muſt be ſuch a <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom;</hi> But ſo It is, by plain <hi>Doctri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal,</hi> and by the <hi>Prophetical Scriptures</hi> of the <hi>Revlation</hi> compared: There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore <hi>There</hi> muſt be ſuch a <hi>Kingdom.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Arg 2.</label> If All <hi>Saints</hi> be <hi>Saints Dead in Chriſt Riſing firſt,</hi> or of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection;</hi> Or <hi>Saints,</hi> Styled The <hi>Lrving,</hi> The <hi>Remaining,</hi> not <hi>Dying,</hi> but <hi>Chang'd</hi> in the very Moment of that <hi>First Reſurrection;</hi> ſo putting off this Low State of <hi>Body,</hi> but not immediately <hi>Caught up</hi> to <hi>Chriſt;</hi> nor Immediately <hi>putting on the Incorruption</hi> and <hi>Immortality</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> but Secured for it by this <hi>Change;</hi> as being <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers of the Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> over <hi>Whom the Second Death ſhall have no power.</hi> And if there be a <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> between this <hi>Change</hi> at the Time of the <hi>Saints Riſing firſt,</hi> before the Time of theſe <hi>Living, theſe Remaining Saints</hi> being <hi>Caught up;</hi> All which Time the <hi>Saints</hi> of both Kinds <hi>Reign with Chriſt;</hi> Then there Muſt be ſuch a <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt.</hi> But ſo all this is by plain <hi>Doctrinal,</hi> and by the <hi>Prophetical Scripture</hi> of the <hi>Reſurrection</hi> Compar'd; Therefore there muſt be ſuch a <hi>Kingdom.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Argum. 3.</label> If Chriſt, and the <hi>Saints</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection</hi> are in the Palace of the <hi>New Heaven above,</hi> as on <hi>Thrones,</hi> and their <hi>Glory ſhining down</hi> on the <hi>New Earth below;</hi> and the <hi>Saints,</hi> the <hi>Living,</hi> the <hi>Remaining Chang'd,</hi> are in the <hi>Paradiſe</hi> of the <hi>New Earth below,</hi> and <hi>walk in the Light of the New Jeruſalem Above;</hi> and ſo Each in this <hi>Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Years, Reign with Chriſt;</hi> and at the <hi>End</hi> the <hi>Saints below,</hi> are <hi>Caught up Alike with the Saints Above,</hi> Then there muſt be a <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt:</hi> But ſo it is by the Compare of <hi>plain Doctrinal</hi> and of <hi>Prophetical Scripture</hi> in the <hi>Revelation;</hi> Therefore ſuch a Kingd. muſt be.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Arg. 4.</label> If <hi>Satan</hi> the <hi>Old Serpent</hi> Bound, muſt Lie a 1000 <hi>Years,</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving his <hi>Head Broken</hi> by the <hi>Second Adam,</hi> the <hi>Seed of the Woman,</hi> and <hi>Bruiſed under the Feet of Saints ſhortly;</hi> and then be <hi>Looſed</hi> for a <hi>Little ſpace</hi> before he be <hi>Caſt into the Lake,</hi> which can never yet have been: Then there muſt be a <hi>Kingdom of a Thouſand Years</hi> to <hi>Chriſt and his Saints.</hi> But ſo by <hi>plain Doctrinal Scripture</hi> and the <hi>Prophetical Scripture</hi> of the <hi>Revelation,</hi> It muſt be; Therefore there muſt be ſuch a <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of a Thouſand Years.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Argum. 5.</label> If the <hi>Dead Wicked Raiſed,</hi> as at the ſame Time with the <hi>Saints of the First Reſurrection,</hi> and with the <hi>Saints chang'd;</hi> and yet being <hi>Raiſed to Condemnation,</hi> are neither counted <hi>Principals</hi> nor <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers</hi> of the <hi>Firſt Reſurrection,</hi> but the <hi>Dead</hi> ſtill; who with <hi>Death</hi> it ſelf muſt be the <hi>Footstool of Christ's Feet,</hi> Sitting on an <hi>Exalted Throne Above Them,</hi> and as <hi>Aſhes</hi> under the <hi>Soals</hi> of the <hi>Saints Feet</hi> for a <hi>Thouſand
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:50119:14"/> Years,</hi> before They are Finally after the 1000 <hi>Y. Destroyed,</hi> and <hi>Cast into the Lake;</hi> Then there muſt be ſuch a <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Christ:</hi> But ſo It muſt be by <hi>plain Doctrinal Scripture,</hi> and by the <hi>Prophetical Scri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pture</hi> of the <hi>Revelation</hi> Compard. <hi>Therefore ſuch a Kingdom muſt be.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Argum 6.</label> If the <hi>Gog-Magog</hi> in the <hi>Revelation,</hi> of which <hi>Ezekiel</hi>'s <hi>Prophecy</hi> is a Great <hi>Type,</hi> c 38. c. 39. that ſtirs not for the <hi>Thouſand Years</hi> of <hi>Satan Bound under</hi> the <hi>Reign of Chriſt with his Saints,</hi> againſt the <hi>Belo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved City</hi> and <hi>Camp of the Saints;</hi> but at the End of the <hi>Thouſand Years,</hi> makes a ſhort <hi>Aſſault,</hi> is no other than the <hi>Wicked Dead Rais'd,</hi> and <hi>Ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> at the <hi>Fotſtool</hi> of <hi>Christ</hi> on his <hi>Throne for a Thouſand Years,</hi> then <hi>Judg'd and Caſt into the Lake</hi> with <hi>Death and Hell;</hi> Then there muſt be ſuch a <hi>Thouſand Years Kingdom of Chriſt:</hi> But ſo it muſt needs be by <hi>plain Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrinal</hi> and the <hi>Prophetical Scripture</hi> of the <hi>Revelation</hi> Compar'd. <hi>There<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore</hi> ſuch a Kingdom muſt be.</p>
            <p>And thus according to both <hi>plain and Doctrinal,</hi> and <hi>Prophetical Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture;</hi> The laſt <hi>Enemy Death</hi> ſhall be <hi>ſubdued,</hi> with <hi>Satan</hi> its <hi>Prince,</hi> and all its <hi>Dead;</hi> and in the <hi>New Heaven and Earth flying away,</hi> the <hi>Kingdom is Delivered up,</hi> and <hi>God All in All.</hi>
            </p>
            <div type="section">
               <head>By way of Addition upon All This.</head>
               <p>
                  <label>Inferential Argum.</label> If at the <hi>Reformation,</hi> Beginning by <hi>Luther, A. D.</hi> 1517. The Laſt 180 of the 1200 Years, Aſſigned to the <hi>Tyranny of Antichrist,</hi> and to the <hi>Witneſſes</hi> in <hi>Sackcloth,</hi> Began, and ſo at the Ending of thoſe 180. <hi>A.D.</hi> 1697. <hi>Daniel</hi>'s <hi>Fourth Monarchy</hi> is at an End, and the <hi>Kingdom</hi> of the <hi>Stone</hi> and of the <hi>Son of Man, Filling the whole Earth</hi> ſhall Begin; and the <hi>Kingdoms of this World</hi> ſhall be Proclaimed to be the <hi>Kingdoms of the Lord,</hi> and of <hi>his Chriſt,</hi> in order to a 75 Y. Preparation to the <hi>Glorious Kingdom of the Thouſand Years.</hi> Then the Time is ſo near that it ought to call us off from this World to a Faith in, Earneſt Prayer for, and Preparation for this <hi>Kingdom:</hi> But <hi>this</hi> hath been Argued on <hi>Great Scri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pture Grounds;</hi> Therefore ſo we ought to be Affected, <hi>Loving this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi> and <hi>Appearance of the Lord Jeſus Coming Quickly.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>AMEN.</closer>
            </div>
            <div type="table">
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <head>Revel. 20. Verſe 4, <hi>&amp;c</hi> Expounded by <hi>Parallels</hi> of its own.</head>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Ver. 4. <hi>I ſaw Thrones, and They ſate upon Them.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Viz.</hi> The Armies of Heaven, <hi>cap</hi> 19. 14 Prophets, Saints, Small, Great, Fearing God Rewarded, <hi>cap.</hi> 11 18.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Peculiarly John <hi>ſaw the Souls of the Beheaded for the Witneſs of Jeſus, and the Word of God.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Viz.</hi> The Souls of the Slain for the Word of God, and the Teſtimony of Jeſus, under the <hi>Pagan Empire, cap.</hi> 6. 9. Then in white Robes, as Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit, Now Living and Reigning in Bodies of Glory; as Intimated then.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Moſt peculiarly, <hi>Thoſe who had not worſhipped the Beaſt,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Viz.</hi> The Witneſſes He kill'd, <hi>cap.</hi> 11. 7. His Image caus'd to be kill'd, <hi>c</hi> 13 15. <hi>viz.</hi> The Reſt of Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low Servants, Brethren, to be kill'd, <hi>c.</hi> 6 11.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>V. 5. <hi>The Remnant, or Reſt of the Dead Lived not,</hi> &amp;c.</cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Viz</hi> The Remnant ſlain with the Sword of Chriſt's Mouth, being Kings, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Small, Great, <hi>cap.</hi> 19. 21. The Dead judg'd, and Thoſe de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy'd, who deſtroy'd the Earth, <hi>cap.</hi> 11. 18.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>V. 6. <hi>Bleſſed and Holy is he that hath his part,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>They Lived and Reigned.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Viz.</hi> The Nations of the Saved; Kings of the Earth, <hi>c.</hi> 21. 24. Healed with the Leaves of the Tree of Life, <hi>cap.</hi> 22. 2.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="query">
               <p>An ANSWER is Deſired to a DISCO<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RSE Annex'd.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:50119:15"/>
            <head>Some Short Additional Remarks, taking off what may ſeem to Weaken the former ARGUMENTS.</head>
            <p>
               <label>Rem 1.</label> THE <hi>New Jeruſalem</hi> Revel. 21. Can neither be the State of <hi>Saints</hi> in the <hi>Higheſt Heavens</hi> to <hi>Eternity,</hi> As Some; Nor any <hi>Excellent State of the Church</hi> on Earth, As Others would ſuppoſe: It cannot be the <hi>State</hi> in <hi>Heaven;</hi> For the <hi>New Jeruſalem</hi> is firſt by the <hi>Apostle Paul,</hi> ſaid to be <hi>Above,</hi> Galat. 4 26. and to be the <hi>Heavenly Jeruſalem,</hi> Heb. 12. 22. Then Three times in the <hi>Revelation,</hi> It is ſaid to <hi>Come down from God out of Heaven.</hi> Not only from <hi>Heaven,</hi> but from <hi>God out of Heaven,</hi> Chap. 3. 12. Chap. 21. 2. and Verſ 10. And upon it, <hi>The Tabernacle of God</hi> is ſaid <hi>To be with Men.</hi> Now if this were a Going up to God into Heaven, the <hi>Apostle</hi> had Inverted all; And what he ſays, is a <hi>Coming down,</hi> muſt be a <hi>Going up:</hi> As if One ſhould Look up, and ſay, <hi>Oh Earth,</hi> and <hi>Look down,</hi> and ſay, <hi>Oh Heaven;</hi> And whereas on this Account, He ſays, <hi>The Tabernacle of God is with Men,</hi> It ſhould rather be ſaid, <hi>The Tabernacle of Men is with God.</hi> When therefore plain <hi>Doctrinal Scripture</hi> ſays, the <hi>New Jeruſalem is Above,</hi> and the <hi>Prophetick Scripture</hi> ſays, <hi>It comes Down from God Out of Heaven,</hi> What can be more Aſſuring? It is not the Going Up of <hi>Saints</hi> to <hi>Heaven.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>On the other ſide, If it were a <hi>State of Saints in Glory on Earth,</hi> Diſtinct from the <hi>Saints in Heaven;</hi> How does the <hi>Apostle</hi> ſay, in that, <hi>Gal.</hi> 4. <hi>The Jeruſalem Above is the Mother of us All;</hi> And ſo the <hi>Bride, the Lamb's Wife?</hi> Whereas the <hi>Jeruſalem on Earth</hi> would be the <hi>Bride,</hi> the <hi>Lamb's Wife;</hi> and ſo the <hi>Mother:</hi> And how did he ſay, <hi>You are come to the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venly Jeruſalem,</hi> and to the <hi>Spirits of just Men made perfect?</hi> viz. In Bodies of Glory Coming Down from the <hi>Manſions in the Father's Houſe,</hi> into the Place of the <hi>New Jeruſalem, Chriſt</hi> went to <hi>prepare for them,</hi> and to <hi>Receive them in unto himſelf,</hi> Even in the <hi>Kingdom he went to receive,</hi> Joh. 14 2. with <hi>Luke</hi> 19 This is the <hi>Myſtery of Marriage between Christ and his Church,</hi> which He <hi>Preſents to Himſelf</hi> without <hi>Spot</hi> or <hi>Wrinckle,</hi> or <hi>Any ſuch Thing;</hi> Which therefore can be no Other than the <hi>General Aſſembly,</hi> and <hi>Church of the Firſt Born,</hi> even of all <hi>Saints written in Heaven,</hi> both Above and Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, who are the <hi>Bride</hi> and the <hi>Lamb's Wife.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Re 2.</label> Whereas Some would have the <hi>Proton</hi> or <hi>Firſt</hi> applyed to the <hi>Saints Riſing,</hi> 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 4 16, 17. and the <hi>Epita,</hi> or <hi>Afterward,</hi> Applyed to the <hi>Saints,</hi> The <hi>Living,</hi> the <hi>Remaining Caught up,</hi> to be words only of Order, without Diſtance of Time, as they are uſed. 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 12. 28. Of <hi>Firſt Apostles,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Afterward Miracles.</hi> I urge it cannot be ſo; For upon this very Suppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſal, <hi>Firſt</hi> and <hi>Afterward,</hi> muſt ſignifie either Difference of Order, of Time, or Both: When then Difference of Order cannot be, there
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:50119:16"/> muſt be Difference of Time; But the <hi>Saints Riſing,</hi> and being <hi>Caught up,</hi> are All of One Order, being Both Alike <hi>Saints;</hi> even the <hi>Saints changed</hi> and <hi>Caught up</hi> are the <hi>Wee All,</hi> of <hi>Saints,</hi> and alſo alike Happy; <hi>For We are ever with the Lord:</hi> So the <hi>Firſt</hi> and the <hi>Afterward</hi> being not of Order muſt have the ſame Force to Diſtinguiſh Time; <hi>viz.</hi> of the 1000 <hi>Y.</hi> as They Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtinguiſh now near 1700 between <hi>Chriſt the Firſt Fruits,</hi> and <hi>His at his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the Reſurrection;</hi> and the <hi>Natural Firſt,</hi> the <hi>Spiritual Afterward;</hi> viz. From the Beginning of the World, to the <hi>Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> 1 Cor. 15. v. 23. and v 46. And hereupon indeed follows a Diſtance of Order; <hi>Saints Raiſed Incorruptible,</hi> of the <hi>First Reſurrection; Saints Chang'd, Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers of the Firſt Reſurrection;</hi> Not putting on <hi>Abſolute Incorruption,</hi> Till <hi>Caught up;</hi> Yet on whom the <hi>Second Death hath no power.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Rem. 3.</label> Whereas by our Tranſlation, and general Interpretation, <hi>The Living, The Remaining,</hi> are ſuppoſed to mean Thoſe who in ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Providence happen to <hi>Remain Alive at the Coming of Chriſt:</hi> It will by Four Geat Reaſons appear; A <hi>State, Order,</hi> and <hi>Generation</hi> of <hi>Saints</hi> is Intended.</p>
            <p n="1">1. The Word <hi>Lipomeni,</hi> joyned with <hi>peri,</hi> ſignifies <hi>Left under ſome Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial Deſignation and Care:</hi> So Theſe <hi>Saints;</hi> In regard of <hi>Saints,</hi> with <hi>Chriſt</hi> Above are <hi>Left</hi> to Inhabit the <hi>New Earth Below;</hi> In regard of the <hi>World of <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ngodly</hi> are <hi>Left;</hi> viz. Reſerved, Guarded from the <hi>Perdition of Fire.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. The Order in the Original is not, <hi>Remaining Alive,</hi> or <hi>Living;</hi> but <hi>Living, Remaining,</hi> or <hi>Left:</hi> Whereas, if <hi>Remaining Alive,</hi> had been only meant, <hi>Remaining</hi> had moſt Naturally come Firſt in the <hi>Greek,</hi> as in the <hi>Engliſh.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. To ſhew a High Senſe; The <hi>Apoſtle</hi> ſays not barely, <hi>Living Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining,</hi> but with an Article to Each, <hi>Each</hi> Is made <hi>Emphatick</hi> and <hi>Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtinct;</hi> As if He had ſaid, <hi>The Living, The Left.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="4">4. To give both Certainty and Stronger Impreſſion; It is doubled in the ſame Words, the ſame Order, with the ſame double Article, <hi>The Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers, The Left, The Livers, The Left.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <label>Rem. 4.</label> Whereas the <hi>Changing</hi> hath been generally underſtood to be in order to be <hi>Caught up;</hi> It is much otherwiſe; For the <hi>changing,</hi> and not <hi>changed Incorruptible,</hi> is in order to a Participation of the <hi>Kingdom of God,</hi> (as even the <hi>Living, the Remaining</hi>) on the <hi>New Earth,</hi> before <hi>Caught up In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corruptible,</hi> to a Full Enjoyment Above; which preſent <hi>Fleſh</hi> and <hi>Blood</hi> can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not have. For upon that very occaſion, the <hi>Apoſtle</hi> ſhews the <hi>Great Myſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry</hi> of ſome being <hi>chang'd,</hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15 40. Now if Their <hi>Changing</hi> were only to be <hi>Caught up,</hi> That needed not; For <hi>being caught up,</hi> were it ſelf the high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt <hi>Change,</hi> as in <hi>Enoch, Elias,</hi> our <hi>Lord;</hi> And yet <hi>changing</hi> and being <hi>caught up,</hi> cannot be the ſame; For the <hi>changing</hi> is at the ſame <hi>Twinkling of an Eye,</hi> with the <hi>Dead Saints Raiſed.</hi> The <hi>Catching up</hi> not till <hi>Afterward;</hi> Not to <hi>meet Chriſt with the Saints he brings with him,</hi> and to come down on Earth, (for that could not be, All being in one <hi>Twinkle</hi> nor does Chriſt ſo come down) but to <hi>be for ever with him,</hi> after having been <hi>The Livers, The Left of a Thouſand Years ſpace of Christ's Kingdom.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
